O. H. Robertson Papers 1918-1966 Mss.B.R546
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1918-1966; 3 linear feet
  - Woods, Andrew H (Box 6)
  - Works Progress Administration (Box 6)
  - Wright, Stillman, to Thomas Park (Box 6)
  - Young, Charles (Box 6)
  - Young, Adrian (Box 6)
  - Young Ed (Box 6)
  - Young, Rufus (Box 6)
  - Young, Saul (Box 6)
- Series II. Manuscripts and Notes, ca.1940-1966; 2 linear feet
  Manuscripts, lectures, and some research notes.
  - American Public Health Association. Committee on research and standards-subcommittee on Air Sanitation: Report (Box 7)
  - Bibliography on Glycols (Box 7)
  - Biological Abstracts (Box 7)
  - California. Department of Natural Resources. Division of Fish & Game (Box 7)
  - Campbell, G D: Recent observations on Zulu and Natal Indian Diabetics in Darban (Box 7)
  - Conference on acute respiratory infections among troops in transports - Notes (Box 7)
  - Donaldson, Lauren R (Box 7)
  - in re Ethylene Oxide (Box 7)
  - Gillman, Theodore: Sex incidence of vascular lesions in aging rats in relation to previous pregnancies (Box 7)
  - [Hamburger, Morton] Morphine Experiments - Data (Box 7)
  - Hamburger, Morton: Studies in the pathogenesis of experimental canine pneumococcus. I, II, III (Box 7)
  - Kerr, William J: In the spirit of service (Box 7)
  - Lester, William, Jr.: The lethal effect of triethylene glycol vapor on dried air-borne bacteria - Draft, experimental results, correspondence. (Box 7)
  - Lester, William, Jr.: REport from the Hinsdale Hospital-Sanitarium (Box 7)
  - Moolten, Sylvan E: Association of adrenocortical hyperplasia with coronary disease and diabetes in older persons. (Box 7)
  - Poetry (Box 7)
  - Pneumonia advisory Council of the State of Illinois, 1938-42. (Box 7)
  - Preparation of thyroid tissue for analysis. (Box 7)
  - Radio Program Script: [Pneumonia & propylene glycol] (Box 7)
  - Reading list for pneumonia..., [1938] (Box 7)
  - Robertson, O.H. (manuscripts) (Box 7)
    - Bacteremia (Box 7)
    - Bactericidal action alcohols TEG in vitro - Data (Box 7)
    - Biological surgey of Pullup Lake (Box 7)
    - Blood pressure and heart weight in immature and spawning Pacific salmon (Box 7)
    - Book review (Box 7)
    - Data on fish, 1956-61 (Box 7)
    - Data on Kokanee (Box 7)
    - Data on trout (Box 8)
    - Discussion on "The storage and transportation of blood for military purposes" Dr. De Gowin (Box 8)
    - Dried Bacterial particles. Data (Box 8)
    - The Effect of hydrocortisone on starving inmature rainbow trout (Box 8)
    - Effect of starvation on growth of remaining testes in unilaterally gonadectomized trout... [(Plates & Photograph (Box 8)
    - Examination of skin strips...stream trout. Data (Box 8)
    - Factors influencing the state of dispersion of the dermal melanophores in rainbow trout I (Box 8)
    - Factors influencing the state of dispersion of the dermal melanophores in rainbow trout II (Box 8)
    - Gonadotrophins, sexual maturation, etc. Notebook (Box 8)
    - Hyperadreno criticism in spawning anadromons and lacustrine rainbow trout (Box 8)
    - Hyperadrenocorticism (Box 8)
    - Illustrations for paper concerning canine experimental pneumococcus (Box 8)
    - Journal of No Name Lakes region, Wind River Range, Wyoming, 1942-1942 (Box 8)
    - Kober Medal: Acceptance speech (Box 9)
    - The Lethal effect of triethyleene glycol vapor on dried air-borne bacteria (Box 9)
    - [Melanophore-Concentration effect of pressure on the trout (Box 9)
    - Mouse protection antibodies (Box 9)
    - National Science Foundation: applications for grants (Box 9)
    - Nature of Bacteremia in experimental pneumococcus pneumonia in the dog. (Box 9)
    - No Name Lakes: Data (Box 9)
    - Notes (Box 9)
    - Notes and data for air-borne bacteria papers (Box 9)
      Filed as received
    - Notes for talks (Box 9)
    - Notes in re salmon studies and data (Box 9)
    - Notes in re per cent Iodine determination... hatchery water (Box 10)
    - On the nature of bacteremia in experimental pneumococcal pneumonia in the dog (Box 10)
    - Production of hyperadreno action by ACTH [in fish] (Photos) (Box 10)
    - The Relationship of gonadal maturation to length of life in Pacific salmon (Box 10)
    - Research in progress - list, 1938 (Box 10)
    - Pneumonia statistics, 1929-1938 (Box 10)
    - Project proposal: A study of the behavior and infectiousne of desicated bacterial aerosols... (Box 10)
    - Rainbow trout project (Box 10)
    - References on "Ageing" (Box 10)
    - The relationship of muscle potassium to the melanophore concentration effect of pressure on the trout (Box 10)
    - Report on investigation of cause of death of black crappies in the Harden Farm ponds at 361 El Camino, Salinas (Box 10)
    - Salmon Study - 1961 Status (Box 10)
    - Sea salmon (Box 10)
    - A study of the distribution of pneumococci in the pulmonary lesion of lobar pneumonia (Box 10)
    - A study of the nature of bacteria in experimental lobar pneumonia (Box 10)
    - A study of the pathogenesis of experimental pneumococcus lobar pneumonia in the dog: notes, data, etc. (Box 10)
    - A study of the melanophore...in rainbow trout (Box 10)
    - Sulfapyridine in experimental pneumococci pneumonia in the dog (Box 10)
    - Thyroid experiments on silvery trout, rainbow trout (Box 10)
  - Strehler, Bernand: Some comparisons of the effects of time and high energy radiations on living systems (Box 10)
  - U.S. Army. Central Medical Dept. Laboratories American Expeditionary Forces, France...: Value of blood transfusion and indications for its use in surgical patients. (Box 10)
  - U.S. Army. Epidemiological Board -Report of ad hoc Committee on ventilation and air disinfection (Box 10)
  - U.S. War Department. Minutes of committee meetings (Box 10)
  - Wallace, Helene Mynchenberg. A stain for fibrin... (Box 10)
  - Van Slyke, Donald D.: Quantitative Clinical chemistry, 2 copies (Box 10)
- Series III. Published works by Robertson, 1.5 linear feet
  Reprints of papers written by Robertson. Filed with Printed Materials under call number B R546m.
  - The activating effect of fresh normal serum on the Pneumococcidal-promoting action of the antipneumococcus serum, Type I., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Air-borne infection., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - An attempt to determine the relationship of the spawning act to the subsequent death of the Pacific salmon., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Autohemagglutination experimentally induced by the repeated withdrawal of blood., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The bactericidal action of propylene glycol vapor on microorganisms suspended in air. I., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The bactericidal action of propylene glycol vapor on microorganisms suspended in air. II. The influence of various factors on the activity of the vapor., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Bactericidal effects of propylene and triethylene glycol vapors on airborne Escherichia coli., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Blood volume in wounded soldiers. I. II., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The cause of death of the Pacific salmon after spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Changes in plasma 17-hydroxycorticosteriods accompanying sexual maturation and spawning of the Pacific salmon and rainbow trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Changes occurring in the macrophage system of the Lungs in pneumococcus lobar pneumonia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A comparative study of phagocytosis and digestion of pneumococci by macrophages and polymorphonuclear leucocytes in normal and immune dogs., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The construction and operation of experimental rooms for the study of air-borne infection., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Control of air-borne infections., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The cultivation and biological characteristics of spirochaeta obermeieri, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    (recurrentis).
  - The dangerous carrier of hemolytic streptococci., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Degenerative changes in the cardiovascular system of spawning Pacific salmon., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A device for automatically controlling the concentration of glycol vapors in the air., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Disinfection of air by germicidal vapors and mists., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Disinfection of the air with Triethylene glycol vapor., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The dispersal of respiratory pathogens in relation to the occurrence and control of air-borne infections., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - An ecological study of two high mountain trout lakes in the Wind River range, Wyoming., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of antiplatelet serum on blood platelets and the experimental production of purpura hemorrhagica., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effects of experimental plethora on blood production., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The Effect of hydrocortisone on immature rainbow trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of increased antipneumococcal immunity on the iception of experimental lobar pneumonia in the dog., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of the gas flame in the adjustment of reaction of sterile solutions., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of triethylene glycol vapor on air-borne beta hemolytic streptococci in hospital wards. I., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of triethylene glycol vapor...in Hospital wards. II. The combined action of glycol vapor and dust control measures., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The effect of triethylene glycol vapor...in hospital wards. III. The action of glycol vapors at low relative humidities., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Experimental air-borne influenza infection. I. Influence of humidity on survival of virus in air., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Experiments on the production of specific antisera for infections of unknown cause. I. II., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Expulsion of Group A Hemolytic streptococci in droplets and droplet nuclei by sneezing, coughing and talking., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Factors influencing the state of dispersion of dermal melanophores in rainbow trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Factors of importance in the use of triethylene glycol vapor for aerial disinfection., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Free antigen and antibody circulating together in large amounts, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    (hemagglutinin and agglutinogen in the blood of transfused rabbits.)
  - Histological changes in the organs and tissues of migrating and spawning Pacific salmon., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Histological changes in the organs and tissues of senile castrated Kokanee salmon., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Histological changes in the pituitary gland of Pacific salmon accompanying sexual maturation and spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Hyperplasia of the adrenal cortical tissue in Pacific salmon and rainbow trout accompanying sexual maturation and spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Immediate Results of splenectomy in pernicious anemia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The influence of relative humidity on the survival of respiratory pathogens dispersed into the environment., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - An instance of lobar pneumonia acquired in the laboratory., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Investigation of the aging process., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Lasting individual differences in the resistance of normal bloods to shak, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The lethal effect of triethylene glycol vapor on air-borne bacteria and influenza virus., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The lethal effect of triethylene glycol vapor on dried air-borne bacteria, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Local recovery in experimental pneumococcus lobar pneumonia in the dog., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Maturation of the infantile testes in rainbow trout produced by salmon pituitary gonadotrophins administered in cholesterol pellets., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The mechanism of interlobar spread in experimental pheumococcus pneumonia in the dog., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The mechanism of natural immunity to pneumococcus infection in mammals., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Medical Research Committee. Wound shock and haemorrhage. (see No. IV, VI, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A method for maintaining stability in reaction of solutions during sterilization., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A method for securing stomach contents of live fish., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A method of citrated blood transfusion., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A new approach to the control of air-borne infection., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - New methods for the control of air-borne infection with especial reference to the use of triethylene glycol vapor., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The normal fate of erythrocytes. I. The findings in healthy animals., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The normal fate of erythrocytes. II. Blood destruction in plethoric animals and in animals with a simple anemia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The oil treatment of bedclothes for the control of dust-borne infection. I. Principles underlying the development and use of satisfactory oil-in-water emulsion., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The oil treatment of bedclothes...infection. II. The use of triton oil emulsion as a routine laundry procedure., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - On the nature of bacteremia in experimental pneumococcal pneumonia in the dog. I. Relationship of natural pneumococcidal-promoting activity of the serummto blood invasion, Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - On the nature of bacteremia...in the dog. II. Disappearance of pneumococci from the circulation in relation to the bactericidal action of the blood in vitro., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Peking Union Medical College Department of Medicine., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Physical signs and roetgenographic findings in lobar pneumonia in adults., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Physician's pneumonia handbook., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Physilogical changes occurring in the blood of the Pacific salmon accompanying sexual maturation and spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The present status of glycol vapors in air sterilization., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Presentation of Kober Medal to Peyton Rous., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The production of experimental influenza in mice by inhalation of atmospheres containing influenza virus dispersed as fine droplets., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The production of experimental Plaut-Vincent's angina in the dog., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The protection of mice against infection with air-borne influenza virus by means of propylene glycol vapor., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Prolongation of the life span of Kokanee salmon by castration before beginning of gonad development., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The rate of bactericidal action of triethylene glycol vapor on microorgar dispersed into the air in small droplets., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Recent studies on the control of dust-borne bacteria by treatment of floors and bedclothes with oil., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Recent studies on experimental lobar pneumonia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The relation of circulating antipneumococcal immune substances to the course of lobar pneumonia. II. Acquired immune substances., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Relation of gonadal maturation to length of life in Pacific salmon., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The relation of natural humoral antipneumococcal immunity to the inception of lobar pneumonia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The relationship of infecting dosage, leucocytic response, bacteremia, and extent of pulmonary involvement to the outcome of experimental lobar pneumonia in the dog., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - The relationship of muscle potassium to the melanophore-concentration effects of pressure on the trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Sources of the antibodies developing after repeated transfusion., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Special investigation committee on surgical shock and allied conditions. No.4. Memorandum on blood transfusion., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Special investigation committee on surgical shock and allied conditions. No. 6. Memorandum on blood volume after haemorrhage., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Sterilization of air by certain glycols employed as aerosols., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Sterilization of air by means of germicidal aerosol mists and vapors., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Sterilization of air with glycol vapors., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Studies on the Pathogenesis of experimental pneumococcus pneumonia in the dog. I. Secondary pulmonary lesions. Relationship of bronchial obstructi and distribution of pneumococci to their inseption., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Studies on the pathogensis of experimental pneumococcus pneumonia in the dog. II. Secondary pulmonary lesions. Their production by intratracheal and intrabronchial injection of fluid pneumonic exudate., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Studies on pneumococcus growth inhibition. II. A method for demonstrating the growth-inhibitory and bactericidal action of normal serum-leucocyte mixtures., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Studies on pneumococcus growth inhibition. VII. The relation of opsonins to natural resistance against pneumococcus infection., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Studies on the transmission and control of respiratory disease within army barracks., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of a case of paroxysmal hemoglobinuria., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the bactericidal activity in vitro of certain glycols and closely related compounds., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the cause of death of the Pacific salmons after spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the effect of oiled floors and bedding on the incidence of respiratory disease in new recruits., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the hemolytic activity of the spleen in pernicious anemia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the macrophage reaction in the pulmonary lesions of dogs with experimental pneumococcus lobar pneumonia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the melanophore-concentrating effect of mammalian throid extract in rainbow trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the mechanism of recovery from lobar pneumonia., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the nature and control of air-borne infection in army camps., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of repeated attacks of experimental pneumococcus lobar pneumonia in dogs., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - A study of the resistance of normal human beings to recently isolated strains of pathogenic pneumococci., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Survival of precociously mature King salmon male parr after spawning., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Tests for the chronic toxicity of propylene glycol and triethylene glycol on monkeys and rats by vapor inhalation and oral administration., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Thyroid hyperplasia and tissue iodine content in spawning rainbow trout: a comparative study of Lake Michigan and California searum trout., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Transfusion with preserved red blood cells., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Transmission and control of respiratory disease in army barracks. IV. The effect of oiling procedures on the incidence of respiratory diseases and hemolytic streptococcal infections., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Urobilin in the stool - and index to blood destruction., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Urobilin in the stool in pernicious anemia as influenced by splenectomy, transfusion and salvarsan., Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
- Series IV. Published works by others, 1.5 linear feet
  Reprints received by Robertson. Filed with Printed Materials under call number B R546mo.
  - Abrams, Gerald D., The influence of somatotropin and corticotropin on the islets of langerhans of the rat.
  - Allison, Leonard N., Advancements in prevention and treatment of parasitic diseases of fish.
  - Ashley, Laurence M., Multiple metastasis of rainbow trout hepatoma.
  - Baggerman, Bertha, Factors in the diadromous migrations of fish.
  - Baggerman, Bertha, Salinity preference, thyroid activity and the seaward migration of four species of Pacific salmon
  - Baker, Burton L., Increase in glyceride content of brown fat by treatment with adrenocorticotropin.
  - Baker, Burton L., The induction of involution in the male reproductive system by treatment with adrenocorticotropin.
  - Baker, Burton L., The histology of the lymphoid organs of rats treated with adrenocorticotropin.
  - Ball, J. N., Reproduction in female bony fishes
  - Barrett, Thomas, Pioneer in the use of triethylene glycol for air sterilization
  - Bern, Howard A., Effect of corticoids on spleen of the Cichlid fish
  - Black, Edgar C., Alterations in glycogen, glucose, and lactate in rainbow and kamloops trout following muscular activity.
  - Black, Edgar C., Changes in pH, carbonate, and lactate of the blood of yearling Kamloops trout during and following severe muscular activity
  - Black, Edgar C., Energy stores and metabolism in relation to muscular activity in fishes
  - Black, Edgar C., Hyperactivity as a lethal factor in fish
  - Black, Edgar C., Increase in levels of lactic acid in the blood of cutthroat and steelhead trout following handling a live transportation
  - Bole, Giles G., Jr., The effect of hypophyseal hormones on the lipid content of brown adipose tissue
  - Bondy, Philip K., Demonstration of Cortisol in fish blood
  - Briggs, John C., Behavior pattern in migratory fishes
  - Brown, J. H., Influence of particle size upon the retention of particulate matter in the human lung
  - Cable, Louella E., A cheek tag for marking fish, with semi-automatic pliers for application of tag
  - Cannon, Paul R., The influence of cortisone upon protein metabolish
  - Coggeshall, Lowell T., Tests for pneumococcus hypersensitiveness in dogs after recovery from experimental pneumococcus lobar pneumonia
  - Cohn, Alfred E., The development of the harveian circulation